Jens Johnson Software Engineer, Nike



303-918-7742

iens@jens-johnson.com

github.com/jens-johnson

linkedin.com/in/jens-johnson

twitter.com/JensJohnson9

iens-johnson.com

SUMMARY

Software engineer with the Nike Sport Science Platform currently based in the Denver, Colorado area. Passionate about exploring the intersection of technology and innovation through software design, development and project execution, and interested in the areas of data and analytics, user experiences, and service-oriented architectures.

EDUCATION

University of Oregon | Eugene, OR | 2015 - 2019

Summit Scholar | Dean's List Recipient

Computer and Information Science, B.S.

Independent research program in mobile application development; coursework includes operating systems, programming language design, data structures and algorithms, computer graphics, and game programming.

Business Administration, B.S.

OCG project manager, UO sales club member, business analytics tutor; coursework includes finance, economics, accounting, marketing, strategic environmental sustainability and management, sports business, and new business venture development.

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer, Nike Sport Science Platform

Nike | Beaverton, OR | August 2020 - Present

Currently a software engineer with the Nike Sport Science Platform (SSP), which provides the data collection and pipeline, study tooling, and user experiences that enable world-class sport research through the Nike Sport Research Lab (NSRL) and Nike Innovation. Responsible for the design, development, and maintenance of solutions that enable sport research, including:

- + Creating data pipelines and services to provide Nike researchers with rapid, reliable, and secure access to sport research data; using cloud-native solutions built on tools such AWS Lambda, EC2, DynamoDB and SageMaker.
- + The full-stack development of research applications using frameworks such as Express and Vue to support critical functions like study management, data retrieval and analysis, and external user research participation.
- + Engaging with internal stakeholders across Nike research and innovation to iteratively design and develop solutions and experiences for Nike researchers, study facilitators, data scientists, athletes, and consumers.

Product Owner, Nike Music

Nike | Beaverton, OR | March 2020 - August 2020

Acting product owner for Nike Music. Responsible for the oversight of the product management, evaluation, and growth strategies to support music and audio-visual activations throughout the entire brand experience, including promotions and marketing, corporate events, and throughout Nike-owned retail stores and infrastructure across the globe.

- + Coordinated multi-regional, multi-dimensional AV and music strategies to deliver targeted brand experiences globally for consumers with internal partners including Nike Global Technology, Nike Global Marketing, and Nike Direct.
- + Facilitated vendor relationships for Nike's store technology partnerships to develop and design integrations within the store technology landscape and AV strategies for Nike retail footprints at scale.
- + Assisted with the creation of a store safety and readiness protocol for Nike retail stores and corporate buildings following the outbreak of COVID-19 to deliver messaging and alerts using existing AV infrastructures.

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer, Product Data Hub/API 360

Nike | Beaverton, OR | August 2019 - March 2020

Software engineer on the Product Data Hub (PDH)/API 360 team within Nike's enterprise data and analytics organization. Responsible for the development and maintenance of applications in the Nike Data Foundation (NDF) platform to deliver dimensional and transactional data products to Nike consumers, supporting functions across the company including e-commerce, marketing, and product design and development.

- + Developed and maintained applications to support multiple data access patterns for internal consumers, including data lakes, warehousing, streaming, and services; using tools such as AWS Lambda/Batch/Kinesis, Apache Spark, Snowflake, and Kafka.
- Led the design, creation, and implementation effort of an automated solution using Git hooks to verify, consolidate, and deploy SQL scripts to a Snowflake data warehouse, allowing data engineers to automatically implement data transformations through version control.
- + Created a search filtering tool using GraphQL, allowing API 360 consumers to execute complex queries on transactional data products across multiple Elastic Search clusters, simplifying and centralizing the data retrieval process.

Software Engineering Intern, Go-To Market Solutions

Nike | Beaverton, OR | June 2018 - August 2018

Software engineering intern with the Go-To Market Solutions (GTMS) team as a member of Nike Global Technology's summer internship program. Helped develop and maintain software solutions for Nike.net – Nike's commercial sales platform.

- + Supported Nike.net content authors through the development of Adobe Experience Manager (AEM) components using Java Spring to deliver customized content authoring including enhanced content previews and interactive page components.
- + Improved Nike marketing content creation pipelines by providing developer tooling for Nike.net, allowing authors and developers to simulate the website experience from different geographies and end-user personas.
- + Participated in end-user design development with cross-functional groups across Nike Marketing, Nike Global Technology, and Nike Direct.

Project Manager, Oregon Consulting Group

Oregon Consulting Group | Eugene, OR | August 2017 - June 2019

Project manager with the Oregon Consulting Group; a student-led, professionally managed organization partnered with the University of Oregon. Responsible for the oversight, management, and execution of consulting projects in areas including market research, financial analysis, and business design and strategy for clients in and around the Pacific Northwest.

- + Developed an omnichannel e-commerce market entry and growth strategy for a consumer goods company, leveraging SEO tools like Google Analytics to identify valuable potential market segments.
- + Created a micro-financing analysis of the State of Oregon for a non-profit trust organization, which provided insight into financing gaps for at-risk/under-privileged communities across the state.
- + Oversaw and aided the professional development of student consultants through coaching, skill enrichment, and individualized growth strategies.

Staff Consultant, Oregon Consulting Group

Oregon Consulting Group | Eugene, OR | December 2016 - August 2017

ORGANIZATIONS AND ACTIVITIES

3rd Place, HACK72 Beaverton, OR | August 2018

3rd place finalist of Nike's HACK72
hackathon; created a fully-functional iOS
application with RFID, Amazon Lex, and
Sports Radar integrations that directed
users to Nike products using NFC-enabled
Nike jerseys and device voice commands
for Nike player products in live events.

Unit Leader, Camp Kesem Gresham, OR | January 2017 - June 2019

Supervised several camp groups for Camp Kesem, an organization providing a summer camp and programs aimed at empowering and supporting children of parents with cancer; as well as developed fundraising, training, and communication materials through year-around efforts.

Wine Marketing, GEO

Siena, Italy | June 2017 - July 2017

Member of Global Education Abroad (GEO)'s wine marketing program; worked with Tuscan wine consortia to develop marketing plans, with a focus on the American import market, including a digitally-focused integrated marketing strategy for the Chianti Classico wine consortium.

SKILLS AND PROFICIENCIES

Languages

- + Javascript, Typescript
- + Python
- + Java
- + C
- + C++
- + C#
- + Swift
- + Ruby
- + Bash
- + PHP
- + Markup (HTML/CSS/XML), Pre-Processor (SASS/SCSS)

Technologies, Tools, Frameworks

- + JS Application Frameworks (React, React Native, Vue, Nuxt, Express, GraphQL, Bootstrap, Webpack, Ionic)
- + Database Languages, Frameworks and Tooling (Relational (MySQL, PostgreSQL, RDS), NoSQL (DynamoDB, MongoDB))
- + AWS (EC2, ECS, Lambda, SNS/SQS, Batch, EventBridge)
- + Test Automation (Postman, Jest, Nock, Cypress)
- + Containers (Docker)
- + CI/CD (Jenkins, Travis)
- + Monitoring, Alerting, and Business Intelligence (Splunk, SignalFX, Tableau, Google Analytics, Jupyter)
- + **Design** (Figma, Sketch, Illustrator, Photoshop)
- + Project Management (Jira, Trello)
- + Office (Confluence, Microsoft Office)

Other Competencies and Interests

- + Full-Stack Application Development
- + Data Transformation and Analysis
- + Responsive Web Design
- + API Development
- + Microservice Architectures
- + Visual Interface Design
- + Hybrid and Mobile Application Development
- + Agile Project Management
- + Strategic Planning
- + Peer Coaching and Development